<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Julia Silge</title>
    <link>/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Julia Silge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One year as a data scientist at Stack Overflow</title>
      <link>/blog/one-year-at-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/one-year-at-stack/</guid>
      <description>I recently passed my one-year anniversary of working at Stack Overflow as a data scientist.
I have some very exciting news! I am joining the data team at @StackOverflow. ✨📊✨📊✨ — Julia Silge (@juliasilge) December 13, 2016   Coming to Stack Overflow has been an adventure for me. This is my first time to work at an actual tech company. I have been what I like to think of as “tech adjacent” my whole career, writing code and working on technical questions but never before working at a straight-up web company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Academic Careers for Astronomers and Physicists</title>
      <link>/blog/non-academic-careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/non-academic-careers/</guid>
      <description> Today I’m giving a talk for the Department of Physics and Astronomy at the University of Utah about careers outside academia for astronomers and physicists. Check out my slides here, and links/references from my talk below.
  STEM PhD finishers in the UK (from the Royal Society) Science &amp;amp; Engineering PhDs awarded and faculty positions (from Nature) Declining proposal success rates in astronomy (from the National Science Foundation) Pamela Gay on soft money positions Katie Mack’s Twitter Josh Wills’ Twitter Drew Conway Oliver Keyes on data science David Robinson on building public artifacts  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>